hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so in this session we are going
to look at a real time scenario where uh
you have got a particular um maybe a
transaction ID which you need to now
break it down into different parts
because you need it for further
verification or you need it for
different test steps which require that
part of the transaction ID now it's a
very common scenario which everybody
comes across uh sometime or the other be
uh you are working in a banking
financial application or some other
application which generates some
transaction ID right um so people do
face this issue a a lot of times
and they don't know how to proceed with
this particular problem so I'm going to
tell you how uh to resolve this
particular problem using tosa and you
need to be aware of uh something called
regular expression how it works and how
you can form the regular expression also
how tosa uses the regular expression
okay so I picked up an example and you
can always relate back to your own
scenario but this is uh um the scenario
for us okay so this is the transaction
ID uh which starts with in in and then
uh some Bank uh ID and then some number
followed by another number okay and then
we need to split this into different
parts okay so as you can see this is the
part one uh which contains um a static
text which is in it will always remain
the same then uh part two is um some
text text okay which comes before any
particular number okay which so any text
it it could be any number of characters
not only four characters but any number
of characters which comes before the
numeric part okay then the part three uh
which is of three-digit number okay so
we need to uh specifically extract it as
a three-digit number and then the
remaining part of that particular text
okay so whatever number is after these
three digits we need to put it into part
four okay so these are all the different
uh Parts uh which we need to split from
this particular transaction ID okay and
that is the requirement um so how can
you do this so as I said we need to use
regular expression here and uh in tosa
uh you can use regular expression with
something called named groups okay so in
this uh you will have a buffer name and
a sub expression so that buffer name uh
it is the name of the buffer which will
store the dynamic part of the comparison
and the sub expression would Define the
dynamic part which should be buffered
okay so this you will understand more
when we go ahead and uh implement this
into a test case right so uh let's go
ahead
and uh let's go to test cases section
here uh we will create another test case
and we will call it Rex for now okay
here um I will say
split
transaction okay and then um we will
first use the tbox set
buffer okay
and we will call this
TR okay and then here uh we will store
this particular transaction
ID okay and now uh we need to create
different buffers as you can see here
right so now we have to use uh the same
buffer name but with a reg verification
right so here again on the buffer name
we are going to use trans and here we
are going to write the reix expression
okay so it's a little long Rex
expression so I will try to explain what
it is and how you have formed this okay
so here first we need to use the Rex
expression
okay
and as you can see here this is uh the
description provided and if you look at
the last part which is extracting text
using regular Expressions you will see
this is the syntax okay so rexs then
expression then the group which is um so
buffer name and then sub expression and
then expression
right and so this first part is the
static part then the buffer name okay so
this is the name for the buffer to which
Dynamic part of the comparison is saved
and then the subex expression this the
dynamic part should be buffered right
there's an example also given here um
and the expression verifies of the text
uh label matches the pattern right so uh
this is how it should be done um any
particular scenario where you have to uh
do this you have to use extracting testt
using regular Expressions
okay so uh let's go ahead and form this
regular expression now so we'll start
with Rex okay now inside this uh we are
going to have four different parts right
so we'll start with the first part here
which is called the part one okay you
can give any particular name to this
buffer uh it doesn't matter now this is
the sub expression okay but uh this is
static always so we have written I in
here because it will not change okay now
we'll close this and we will now form
the second part which is the part two
okay we'll save it in part two now here
uh we have got a couple of characters
right so here we will be
using um some regular expression like a
to zed and then I will use the regular
expression star which means uh any text
any particular text with any number of
characters it will be able to identify
that okay now the next part is the
three-digit number which we me to
extract right so we'll form this again
we will name this part
three okay and here uh we'll be using
some other regular expression which will
extract our digits okay so we'll use
slash D and then we require just uh
three digits from here right so we will
specify that so that it extracts only
three digits so now we come to the last
part and here we will name it part
four okay and this uh will be the
remaining uh digits in the ID right so
uh here again we will use
SLT okay and then we will use star so
that it can extract any number of digits
okay then we will close
this and here actually we don't require
this square brackets so I'll remove
this okay so this is our regular
expression which has got four parts you
can see four different buffers so it
will extract each part uh from the
regular expression and then it will
store it into these four different
buffers okay so now uh let's go ahead
and change the work state to complete it
and let's try and execute this
now okay um you will get this particular
error okay if you have not changed the
action mode okay so it will say it has
to be an input value so what you need to
do
here is you need to change this action
mode to
verify
Okay so so whenever uh you are using Rex
to extract text it has to be uh the
action mode verify so let's go ahead and
try this
again okay so this time around it will
pass and now we need to verify whether
these buffers have the correct value or
not okay so that can be done using this
buffer viewer if you go into tools you
will find this particular tool which
contains all the buffers which we have
created okay and if I go here I can also
search my buffers so I will search with
part and it will give me all the
different buffer names with start with
part okay and you can see here so part
one contains the in in value part two
contains uh the four uh banking
abbreviation and part three contains the
three digits and part four contains the
remaining digits okay so this is how you
can extract different uh text or
different values from your buffer and
store it in different buffers now this
could be useful for verification purpose
or it could be used uh for different
test steps
okay so it's a very useful um expression
the Rex expression and it's a very
powerful expression okay so whenever you
want to extract text or you want to
verify certain part of the text
especially when this particular value in
is dynamic in nature okay or the parts
of the values are dynamic in nature in
this type of scenarios you should be
using the Rex
expression that's all for this
particular video if you have any
questions then please leave it in the
comments if you like this video then
please subscribe to our Channel thanks
for watching and I will see you in the
next
video